Rajan Pandey

Python Developer, Data Science

Computer engineering student with motivation and responsibility, pursuing a career as a python developer and data science. Selflearned tool and framework such as Django, machine learning and deep-learning and have good skills and experience in tools and methods. I am able to work well both in a team environment as well as using my own initiative.



12pnrj@gmail.com

9860900031

Kathmandu, Nepal

linkedin.com/in/rajan-pandey-rjnp2-60ba78163

github.com/rjnp2

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Engineering National College of Engineering, Tribhuvan University

10/2016 - 01/2022 Lalitpur, Nepal

Project

 Animal Recognition System. (minor project)

• Facial Landmark Detection. (major project)

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- 1. Animal Recognition System Based On CNN. (05/2019 08/2019) ♂
- Identifying the animal in the images with the help of convolutional neural network in Keras and using Kaggle Animal-10 dataset. And obtains 78% accuracy while validation.
- 2. Facial Landmark Detection using CNN from scratch using numpy. (11/2019 - 02/2021)
- Creating a CNN model to detect facial landmarks in an image and obtaining 0.05 means absolute error. And apply filters according to landmarks points.
- 4. Build full functioning eCommerce site called GreatKart using django3 (09/2021 - No Expires) ☑
- Working with Model, Media Files, Paginator & Search, add to Cart using Session Keys, Increment/decrement/remove Cart Items, Fixing Cart Bugs & Context Processor for Cart Item Counter
- Product Variations & Variation Manager, Registration, login, User Account Activation & Activation Link Expiry and Forgot Password with Secure Validation Links
- Cart Checkout, automatically assign the Cart Items to Logged-in User, Payment **Gateway Integration & Place Order**
- 5. coffee-website and SocialBook using html and pure css (09/2021 - 09/2021)
- Learn and build websites using html and pure CSS (flex-box and grid)
- 6. Stock price of Google using LSTM (12/2019 01/2020) \Box
- By using LSTM technique, predict the Google stock price which is time series data and obtains 0.0219 mean absolute error.
- 8. Text Recognition using CRNN (05/2019 06/2019) □
- Creating a CRNN model to recognize English text in an image using CTC decoder and encoder with validation accuracy of 0.7431.
- 9. Web Scrapping on Cribcuzz and flipkart (12/2020 12/2020) 🗗
- To automatically extracting information from web with images.
- 10. Text Extraction from Image (05/2019 05/2019) ♂
- Extract text from images which is used while recognizing alphabets using opency.
- 11. California Housing Price Prediction (02/2020 03/2020)
 ☐
- To Predict a housing prices using the California house datasets with help of Linear, Lasso and Ridge Regression and also perform exploratory data analysis and outlier treatment.

SKILLS

Python MS-Excel Django SciKit-learn **Pandas** Numpy SQL, MongoDB and Neo4j Llnux Plotly and Dash Opency Keras Seaborn Machine Learning Javascript Deep-learning IBM whatson Studio Heroku Server Html, CSS Google Data Studio

PUBLISH

Journal on "Animal Recognition System Based On CNN". (08/2020 - No Expires)

□

T On NCE Journal of Science & Engineering (NJSE) Vol I, Issue I.

CERTIFICATES

- 1. Microsoft Excel (12/2019 No Expires) Offered by Udemy
- 2. An Introduction to Interactive Programming in Python (Part 1 and 2) (11/2018 - No Expires)

Offered By Rice University on Coursera

- 3. Neural Networks and Convolutional Neural Networks. (10/2019 - No Expires)

 ✓ Offered By DeepLearning.AI on Coursera.
- 4. IBM Data Science Specialization (07/2021 - No Expires) ☑

Offered by IBM on Coursera

5. Introduction to Data Studio (08/2021 - 08/2024) 🗗 Offered by google Analytics academy

Rajan Pandey

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Science Intern

Blackcoffer Consulting

07/2021 - 08/2021

New Delhi, India

Task

- Writing Script and Draft document for text extraction and to fetch data using API on Python.
- Storing and handling fetched data in google big query, create a dashboard from that data on google data studio.
- Deploying and draft document for scripts and checking daily logs of deployed tools in Heroku server.

Django Developer, AI

Mango Software Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

11/2021 - Present

Putalisadak, Kathmandu

Task

- Design and build a Chat-bot from Scratch using Universal Sentence Encoder model and integrated in Django server using restful API and Django channel.
- Integrated our Chat-bot System in Messenger and Viber using their Web-hook.
- Developed Real Time Chat System using Django channel and websocket.
- Developed Real Time Video-Calling System using Django channel (Signaling server) and Web real-time communication API for a single Peer-Peer and try another Conference video calling Architecture such as Multi-point Control Unit (MCU) and Selective Forwarding Unit (SFU) in Django.

WORK SKILLS

Natural Language Processing

Web RTC

Django-restful API

Bert and USE model

Django Channel and Web-Socket

Web-hook Integration

INTERESTS

Traveling

Watching Movies

Photography

Using new devices

Learning AI and Data Science

Sleeping